A. E. Coppard Collection
A. E. Coppard Collection
1921-1952
Coppard, A. E. (Alfred Edgar),1878-1957.
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the English short story writer, poet. Collection consists of 55 outgoing letters (1921-1952); holograph short story manuscripts; and a typescript speech for the opening of the Authors' World Peace Appeal Conference, 1951. Recipients of letters include Frederick T. Bason, Adrian Brunel, Lawrence Drake, Gilbert H. Fabes, Robert Greacen, Isaac Levine, Bruce Marshall, Frederic Prokosch, and Jacob Schwartz, among others.
148903
Biographical History
Alfred Edgar Coppard (1878-1957) was an English author and poet. He is regarded by some as one of the finest short-story writers in the English language.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The A. E. Coppard Collection consists of correspondence and manuscripts.
Correspondence is outgoing only. Recipients of the letters include Frederick T. Bason, Adrian Brunel, Lawrence Drake, Gilbert H. Fabes, Robert Greacen, Isaac Levine, Bruce Marshall, Frederic Prokosch, and Jacob Schwartz. Subjects discussed include his poetry and other writings, the salfe of his manuscripts, the possibility of dramatic or film adaptations, works in progress, planned writing, and activities of the Authors' Peace Appeal.
Manuscripts are three short stories in annotated longhand -- "Silver Circus," "Ugly Anna," and "You Never Know, Do You?" There is also an annotated typescript of his 1951 statements for the Authors' World Peace Appeal Conference, in which he called for an end to the Korean conflict.
One miscellaneous item of Memorabilia is a check endorsed by Coppard,.
For additional information on this collection, see "The A. E. Coppard Papers at Syracuse" in The Courier, vol. 9, no. 3 (April 1972), pp. 32-37.
Arrangement of the Collection
Letters are arranged chronologically. Memorabilia and writings are arranged alphabetically by type.
Related Material
See also the
George Brandon Saul Papers
for additional Coppard material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- British; Activism and social reform; Bason, Frederick T.; Brunel, Adrian.; Coppard, A. E. (Alfred Edgar), 1878-1957.; Drake, Lawrence.; Fabes, Gilbert Henry, 1894-; Greacen, Robert.; Levine, Isaac Don, 1892-; Marshall, Bruce, 1899-; Prokosch, Frederic, 1908-1989.; Schwartz, Jacob.; Authors' World Peace Appeal Conference.; Authors, English -- Political activity.; Authors, English -- Political and social views.; English literature -- 20th century.; Korean War, 1950-1953 -- Political activity.; Pacifism.; Pacifists.; Poets, English.; Correspondence.; Authors.; Pacifists.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Manuscripts gift of Lily Anne Coppard, 1964.
Correspondence purchased, 1964-1979.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing, 1921-1936; 1948-1952, (Box 1)
- Manuscripts
  - Short stories
    - Rifki, 1928[?] (Box 1)
    - Ugly Anna, 1944 (Box 1)
    - You Never Know, Do You?, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Speeches
    - Statement for Authors' World Peace Appeal Conference, 1951 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia
  - Check from the Authors' Syndicate, Ltd., endorsed by Coppard, 20 Nov 1924 (Box 1)